{
  "C":[
        {"name":"Declaration and commenting",
         "id":"1001",
         "questions":[
            {"type": "choice", "question":"How to declare a variable to hold an integer value?", "choices":["var a;", "int a;", "a = 0", "num a;"], "answer":"int a;"},
            {"type": "blank", "question":"How to comment a single line?", "answer":"//" },
            {"type": "choice", "question":"How to do a multi-line comment?", "choices":["<!-- -->", "/* */", "#", "//"], "answer":"/* */"},
            {"type": "choice", "question":"Which is one of the way to declare a string constant?", "choices":["char foo[] = \"foo\"", "String foo = \"foo\"", "chars foo = \"foo\"", "char foo=\"foo\""], "answer":"char foo[] = \"foo\""},
            {"type": "blank", "question": "Name the data type to hold floating point(32-bit) numbers", "answer": "float"},
            {"type": "blank", "question": "What is the qualifier used for representing only non-negative numbers?", "answer":"unsigned"},

          ]
        },

        {
          "name":"Operators",
          "id":"1002",
          "questions":[
            {"type": "choice", "question":"Which is bitwise OR operator?", "choices":["or", "xor", "|", "^"], "answer":"|"},
            {"type": "blank", "question":"What is in bitwise AND operator in C?",  "answer":"&"},
            {"type": "blank", "question":"What is bitwise negation operator in C?",  "answer":"~"},
            {"type": "choice", "question": "Which is conditional ternary operator", "choices":[">>", "?:", "<<", "??"], "answer":"?:"},
            {"type": "blank", "question": "Is there a way to increment and assign a value in a single statement?  If so, what is the operator?", "choices": ["No such operator", "+=", "=+", "&="], "answer": "+="},
            {"type": "choice", "question": "How to multiply two numbers in C, say x, y are the numbers?", "choices": ["x . y", "x mul y", "x * y", "x ** y"]}
          ]
        },

        {
          "name": "Conditions and Loops",
          "id": "1003",
          "questions": [
            {"type": "choice", "question": "Which is basic conditional branching statement in C?", "choices": ["check", "is", "if", "yes"], "answer": "if"},
            {"type": "choice", "question": "What is the syntax for FOR loop?", "choices": ["for ( variable initialization; condition; variable update )",
            "for ( condition; variable update ; exit status)", "for (condition 1; condition 2; condition 3)", "for ( variable increment ; variable decrement; condition )"
            ], "answer": "for ( variable initialization; condition; variable update )"},
            {"type": "blank", "question": "Which looping makes sure loop is executed atleast once?", "choices": ["for", "while", "do..while", "None"], "answer": "do..while"}

          ]
        }

      ],
  "Python":[],
  "JavaScript":[]
}
